# **TOMMY ROSARIO**

### **Seasoned Frontend Developer**

# tjrosario.github.io

Email: tomjasonrosario@gmail.com | Cell: (718) 578 1380



### **ABOUT ME**

I'm a frontend developer based out of the Jersey Shore. I love working on fun, innovative websites. I've been involved in technology for almost two decades now. I'm a bit of a perfectionist and take a lot of pride in all of my work. I try to leave every piece of code a bit more modular, performant and readable than how I found it.

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Frontend Developer**

#### Plixer

Sep 2019 - Present

- Assisted in re-architecting network traffic analysis system from a legacy tech-stack to modern Angular 8+ framework
- Lead development on the application's reporting engine which gives customer's a clear visualization of all network conversation and device usage
- Components and services strongly typed using Typescript
- · Wrote unit tests using Jasmine and Karma
- Implemented Bootstrap for the UI library

Tech Stack: Angular 8+, Typescript, Bootstrap

# **Frontend Engineer**

#### CityBldr

May 2017 – May 2020

- Lead front end developer for both the consumer facing and internal RETech application that determines the best value and uses for land for both sellers and buyers.
- Built property claim flow which allows sellers to register

### **SKILLS**

#### Frontend

react | redux | angular | typescript esnext | javascript | scss | bootstrap material-ui | jest | enzyme | magento

### Middle Tier

nodejs | express | passport | stripe

#### **Backend**

mongodb

## Design

photoshop | zeplin

# **Project Management**

jira | trello | zenhub

# **Repo Platforms**

git | github | gitlab

### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Delaware**

Bachelors of Science, Computer Science and look up their property to determine its worth when sold alone and along with neighbors

- Assisted in building home-grown CRM system that partners could use to manage leads and potential targets
- Helped build a target dispatching platform which automates the process of building a set of target properties for any particular lead run
- Facilitated ongoing upgrades to the front end stack (React)
- State management using Redux
- · Implemented UI components with Material UI
- Lead efforts in the consumer-facing site redesign

Tech Stack: React, Redux, Material UI

# Sr. UI Developer

### **AffinityX**

Jan 2015 - May 2020

- Created new functionality and features for creative content delivery platforms using KnockoutJS, jQuery and PHP
- Helped in building custom application routing system
- Developed re-usable components using KnockoutJS
- Built a custom proofing interface that allows customers to upload creative content, manage revision history and mark for approval
- · Assisted in building administrative console

Tech Stack: KnockoutJS, jQuery, PHP

# **Frontend Engineer**

### ThreadLab, Inc

May 2014 - Jan 2020

- · Lead front end development using Angular 5+, SASS
- Built a proxy using NodeJS for restful API consumption

- Developed build pipeline with Jenkins
- Created responsive layout using SASS/Bourbon
- Implemented recurring subscription system using Recurly
- Integrated Stripe and Paypal payment funnels
- Manage email marketing templates via Mailchimp and Mandrill

Tech Stack: Angular 5+, Typescript, NodeJS, Bourbon

# **Software Engineer**

#### **Do Something**

May 2014 – Jan 2015

- Lead development on various social awareness campaigns
- Creating new features, functionality to application modules using jQuery and RequireJS
- Ongoing maintenance within Drupal framework template system
- Contributed to open-sourced interface framework and pattern libraries

Tech Stack: Drupal 7, jQuery, RequireJS, Bourbon

# Senior Software Engineer

#### CPXi

Oct 2013 - May 2014

- Worked on new functionality and features for company's internal metrics dashboard
- Developed browser plugins that were available in the Chrome and Firefox web stores
- Lead UI development on a real-time news feed application / scraper built on HandlebarsJS, NodeJS, and Sails MVC
- Proprietary CSS framework using LESS

Tech Stack: Handlebars JS, Laravel, Symfony, LESS, NodeJS, Sails

### Frontend Tech Lead

#### **Alexander Interactive**

Jul 2006 - Oct 2013

- Built, managed and lead a team of seven front-end developers
- In charge of providing front-end development estimates on all projects
- Developed and re-wrote several re-usable JavaScript widgets from Prototype JS to jQuery
- Introduced HTML5 and CSS3 to Magento applications
- Defined and authored the company's best practices and coding standards document for front-end development
- Worked closely with IA and Creative departments on defining new and effective user experiences
- Worked closely with backend development team on frontend integration points
- Provided technical direction for clients on front-end handoff projects
- Utilized text replacement technologies such as Typekit, Cufón, sIFR
- Skinned and integrated custom Magento themes
- Object-oriented JavaScript development
- Responsive CSS
- · Parallax UI Development
- Converted Photoshop documents into HTML and CSS templates
- Wrote custom CSS reset framework

**Tech Stack**: jQuery, PrototypeJS, LESS, CSS3, Magento, OfBiz, .NET Web API